<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!-- Created by ModBuddy on 11/23/2013 1:27:25 PM -->
<GameData>
	<Buildings>
		<Row>
			<Type>BUILDING_LEU_WAMPUM_HOUSE</Type>
			<BuildingClass>BUILDINGCLASS_MINT</BuildingClass>
			<Cost>100</Cost>
			<GoldMaintenance>1</GoldMaintenance>
			<PrereqTech>TECH_CURRENCY</PrereqTech>
			<Help>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEU_WAMPUM_HOUSE_HELP</Help>
			<Description>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEU_WAMPUM_HOUSE</Description>
			<Civilopedia>TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEU_WAMPUM_HOUSE_TEXT</Civilopedia>
			<ArtDefineTag>COURTHOUSE</ArtDefineTag>
			<MinAreaSize>-1</MinAreaSize>
			<ConquestProb>66</ConquestProb>
			<HurryCostModifier>25</HurryCostModifier>
			<IconAtlas>LEU_ONONDAGA_TADODAHO_ICON_ATLAS</IconAtlas>
			<PortraitIndex>3</PortraitIndex>
		</Row>
	</Buildings>
	<Building_TerrainYieldChanges>
		<Row>
			<BuildingType>BUILDING_LEU_WAMPUM_HOUSE</BuildingType>
			<TerrainType>TERRAIN_COAST</TerrainType>
			<YieldType>YIELD_GOLD</YieldType>
			<Yield>1</Yield>
		</Row>
	</Building_TerrainYieldChanges>
	<Building_YieldChanges>
		<Row>
			<BuildingType>BUILDING_LEU_WAMPUM_HOUSE</BuildingType>
			<YieldType>YIELD_CULTURE</YieldType>
			<Yield>1</Yield>
		</Row>
	</Building_YieldChanges>
	<Language_en_US>
		<!--UNIQUE 1-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_LEU_FIREKEEPER_HELP">
			<Text>Can be expended at City-States for a burst of and [ICON_INFLUENCE] Influence twice that of what a Great Merchant would get.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LEU_FIREKEEPER">
			<Text>Fire Keeper</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LEU_FIREKEEPER_HELP">
			<Text>Replacement for the Great General. Can be expended at City-States for a burst of and [ICON_INFLUENCE] Influence twice that of what a Great Merchant would get.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LEU_FIREKEEPER_STRATEGY">
			<Text>Fire Keepers are as useful as Great Generals for providing bonuses to your units while in war. However their greatest asset comes from being expended to earn more allies.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_UNIT_LEU_FIREKEEPER_TEXT">
			<Text>The term Fire Keeper was used by the Iroquois to refer to their most influential spiritual leader in New York State; it has been used in this way for centuries.The Tadodaho in New York State is the spiritual leader of the Haudenosaunee, Six Nations that includes the Cayuga, Mohawk, Oneida, Onondaga, Seneca, and Tuscarora people. The post is also called the "Head Chief of All the Six Nations". He presides over the Grand Council of the Haudenosaunee (also called Iroquois). The Great Council Fire of the Iroquois League is still located within the Onondaga reservation in present-day New York. Many of the Iroquois live in Canada, where their ancestors moved after the American Revolutionary War, as they were allies of the defeated British. The Crown gave them some land in compensation for what they lost.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Along with other Native American leaders, the Fire Keeper is responsible for maintaining the history of the Haudenosaunee people. The position of Fire Keeper, also called Tadodaho, is a lifetime appointment. According to tradition, when the previous Tadodaho dies, a council of chiefs from the Haudenosaunee chooses a leader from the Onondaga people.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_PROMOTION_LEU_FIREKEEPER">
			<Text>Tadodaho</Text>
		</Row>

		<!--UNIQUE 2-->
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEU_WAMPUM_HOUSE">
			<Text>Wampum House</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEU_WAMPUM_HOUSE_HELP">
			<Text>The Wampum House is the Iroquois unique Mint. It gives +1 [ICON_GOLD] Gold for each worked Coast tile and +1 [ICON_CULTURE] Culture by itself.</Text>
		</Row>
		<Row Tag="TXT_KEY_BUILDING_LEU_WAMPUM_HOUSE_TEXT">
			<Text>Wampum is a vital part of Onondaga and Haudenosaunee culture. Wampum is created from the shell of a clam. The beads are cut from the white and purple parts of the shell. The pieces are rounded, sanded and drilled to make a bead. Because of the effort that is needed to make a bead, wampum is highly valued.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]The shell is thought of as a living record of the Haudenosaunee. The speaker puts the words of the agreement into the wampum as the strings or belts are woven together. Each speaker thereafter uses the wampum to remember the initial agreement and the history that has happened to date. To us, the belts are our living history.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Wampum has many uses. One of the uses is to invite the other nations to council meetings. These wampum strings are given the topic that all of the nations are to meet and discuss about. At the end of the wampum string is a wooden stick. The wooden stick tells the people of the nation when the meeting is to take place. As each day passes, a notch is cut off the stick and when the notches are all gone, the meeting will take place.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Wampum also symbolizes titles within the Haudenosaunee. Each position of a Clan Mother of a Chief has their own wampum string. When a person holds this title for the Nation, they carry the wampum to show their place in the community. When a leader falls, the wampum is passed on to the new leader.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]When a string of wampum that is held in a person’s hand, they are said to be speaking truthfully. During ceremonies, the wampum strings are used to convey that the speaker’s words are true. People listening to a speaker holding the wampum also know this and are very attentive and respectful of the speaker’s message.[NEWLINE][NEWLINE]Onondaga was given the responsibility of Wampum Keeper of the Haudenosaunee at the founding of the Great Peace. Four countless centuries the Onondaga were the caretakers of the belts. When our white brothers first began interacting with us, they noticed how important the belts were to us. Then after many attempts, New York anthropologists were able to obtain the belts through an illegal sale. The Nation immediately tried to have the belts returned. But the State of New York deemed that these belts were too valuable and needed to placed in the State’s museum for safe keeping. But the Onondaga Nation worked diligently to have the wampum return home. Finally in the fall of 1989, some belts returned after the determined efforts of the chiefs to bring these belts back to the people.</Text>
		</Row>
	</Language_en_US>
</GameData>